<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Events Looped</title>
    <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Events Looped</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ilya Nemtsev 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:33:01 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Use Golang to Upload Files to Azure Blob Storage</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/use-golang-to-upload-files-to-azure-blob-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 17:33:01 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/use-golang-to-upload-files-to-azure-blob-storage/</guid>
      <description>If you are enjoying Go and its community as much as myself but have been using the Azure Cloud Platform for some time already, you will probably want to use Azure Blob Storage at some point. In that case, this blog post is for you.
You will need: The first thing you need to do is make sure you set up your blob storage account in Azure Portal and create a blob container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make Multiple Api Calls At The Same Time With GoRoutines</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/golang-make-multiple-api-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 21:16:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/golang-make-multiple-api-calls/</guid>
      <description>Golang is efficient, very efficient. Much of this efficiency is attributed to its unique abstractions when dealing with concurrency. Java for example, maps its threads to OS threads, while Go uses its own goroutines scheduler to further abstract its lightweight goroutines from OS threads. In short, Golang is very frugal with how it uses OS threads; if a goroutine becomes blocked, Go&amp;rsquo;s scheduler will switch in another goroutine in its place to keep the thread busy as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Developer in 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/becoming-a-developer-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 14:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/becoming-a-developer-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>There has never been a better time to become a web developer than now. The United States Bureau of Labour Statistics predicts an increase of job postings by 15% between 2016-2026, in comparison to 7% average across all occupations. According to ZipRecruiter the current average salary of a Web Developer in United states is $74,080 with top 1% earning $123,000 to $133,000. Among the general specializations of web developers (front-end, back-end and full-stack); full-stack developers on avereage are paid the highest, which is logical since they have to stay up-to date on both back-end and fron-end technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typescript and its future</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/typescript-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2019 17:21:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/typescript-future/</guid>
      <description>Before Angular team decided to turn the its community upside down with the release of Angular 2 in 2016, I did not think Typescript would take off beyond a small loyal group. Having been developed internally my Microsoft, the open source community was wary. But then, the unlikely thing happened, Microsoft and Google joined forces to create Angular (2&amp;hellip;) with TypeScript support out of the box. By default.
You can imagine this gave TypeScript a strong boost in popularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Blog on Azure</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/hugo-blog-on-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 15:51:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/hugo-blog-on-azure/</guid>
      <description>Summary I decided to give blogging a try. I setup the most cost-effective solution I could come up with; static-html hosting on cloud blob-storage.
Initially I tried using Jekyll to generate my static pages, but due to the clunky tooling available (especially on Windows) I looked for other solutions. That is when I found Hugo. They have great documentation, modern CLI and great tooling, regardless of your OS preference.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>