<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>career on EventsLooped</title>
    <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/tags/career/</link>
    <description>Recent content in career on EventsLooped</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Ilya Nemtsev 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:09:54 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.eventslooped.com/tags/career/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m a self taught developer, which websites did I use to learn</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/self-taught-developer-websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 16:09:54 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/self-taught-developer-websites/</guid>
      <description>Looking back, it would of probably been better if I got my Computer Science degree instead of Mathematics. At the very least, it would have made the first few years of my career a whole lot easier. That is one way of looking at it, but would I be a better developer if I had it easier? That is hard to say. But, all those experiences have made me who I am today, and I am happy with where I ended up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a Developer in 2019</title>
      <link>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/becoming-a-developer-in-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 14:41:36 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.eventslooped.com/posts/becoming-a-developer-in-2019/</guid>
      <description>There has never been a better time to become a web developer than now. The United States Bureau of Labour Statistics predicts an increase of job postings by 15% between 2016-2026, in comparison to 7% average across all occupations. According to ZipRecruiter the current average salary of a Web Developer in United states is $74,080 with top 1% earning $123,000 to $133,000. Among the general specializations of web developers (front-end, back-end and full-stack); full-stack developers on avereage are paid the highest, which is logical since they have to stay up-to date on both back-end and fron-end technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>